<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Speech: Emotional Value Part III</title>
    <link href="/2024/11/29/English-1/"/>
    <url>/2024/11/29/English-1/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="Introduction"><a href="#Introduction" class="headerlink" title="Introduction"></a>Introduction</h4><p>Before I begin, I want to emphasize that emotional value is a significant part of our daily lives and relationships. However, with the rise of the modern internet, this value has gradually been distorted.</p>    <br><p>1. Can Emotions Be Valued?“Emotional value” is an intriguing concept in urban society. But have you ever wondered whether our emotions can actually be valued? To explore this, we first need to define emotion: it is our attitude, experience, and behavioral response toward external stimuli. It originates from within and represents our true thoughts.</p>    <br><p>In the past, relationships were more authentic, but over time, they have become increasingly transactional. Today, people often evaluate each other based on their utility or benefit. Emotions, which should be the closest bond between individuals, have become entangled in this dynamic. While emotional value is not inherently bad, when used to measure relationships, it can serve as a façade for our endless pursuit of material gain.</p>    <br><p>2. Balance and CalculationWe must acknowledge that the concept of "emotional value" often stems from constant calculation and balancing. In commerce, we assess utility; in personal life, we hope our loved ones don't calculate our worth. Imagine coming home and your parents refuse to let you eat because they’re displeased with you. How would you feel? (You might want to reconsider this example—it could distract from your point.)</p>    <br><p>Similarly, the emergence of "partner culture" reflects the societal impact on friendships. If someone privately says, “I’m friends with them because they offer emotional value,” wouldn’t that upset you? Such transactional thinking taints genuine connections.</p>    <br><p>3. Emotional ChainPicture this: you’re working or studying, and you have to interact with someone whose beliefs conflict with yours. Both of you suppress your dissatisfaction, pretending everything is harmonious. Eventually, unresolved tension may lead to arguments, public shaming (yes, even hanging names on walls!), or worse, online harassment or even violence.</p>    <br><p>At the outset, your goal was to maintain civility, but when the emotional chain breaks, it causes damage.</p>    <br><p>4. Understanding and Adapting to YourselfFinally, learn to understand and adapt to yourself. I’m reminded of Ove, a character from Fredrik Backman’s novel. He’s an old man, grumpy and stubborn, yet he silently helps maintain his community and supports his friends, even saving them from being sent to nursing homes.</p>    <br><p>The takeaway? Even if you’re not great at offering emotional value, you can still contribute meaningfully to society.</p>    <br><blockquote><p>Summary：    <br><br>Grammar and Sentence Flow: Some sentences were awkwardly phrased. Simplifying them improves clarity.    <br><br>Coherence: Ensure smooth transitions between points for better flow.    <br><br>Word Choice: Terms like “dissimilation” and “utilize value” were replaced for accuracy and naturalness.    <br></p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>English Langugae</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>English Langugae</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>舟渡</title>
    <link href="/2024/11/28/Arknight/"/>
    <url>/2024/11/28/Arknight/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>撰写此文，以纪念那建立blog的岁月。<br>纪念那努力着挣脱孤岛的日子。<br><del>虽然目前还没写完，在努力码字了</del><br><del>期中周事情好多，要忙死了</del></p><h4 id="The-Start"><a href="#The-Start" class="headerlink" title="The Start"></a>The Start</h4><p>不知从何时起便关注到了“个人博客”这个东西，</p><blockquote><p>  2024.10.12 & physnya  <br>   <br>   “感觉不清楚自己是谁......”  <br>   “你不是你吗？”  <br>   “不知道自己现实中是个什么样的人”  <br>   “那谁也不知道，我也不知道自己是谁，但是必须要知道自己要去哪里，从哪里来”  <br>   “总是喊着自己要去为先，但是卷不动了......”  <br>   “那就别卷，说的难听点，认清自己不敢为人先也是一种进步”  <br>   “优柔寡断.jpg，自己总是在果断和犹豫间无限切换”  <br>   “这是性格问题，老是去想这件事反而会内耗，还不如在自己犹豫的时候多犹豫一会儿”  <br>   “思考自我是个好痛苦的事情”  <br>   “那就不要再思考了”  <br>   “高中总是喊着自己要去深圳科高教数学，但是后面梦破碎后面对未来不知所措，作为一个小镇做题家，感觉完全被高中体制化掉了”  <br>   <br>   - 接着也是这个对话的高光时刻 <br>   <br>   “不要这样想，你要是这么给自己打上标签，就很难撕下来了”    <br>   “也不要说什么梦想破碎，破碎的梦多了去了，活在当下才是唯一的解决方案”    <br>   <br>   “活在当下......好难”   <br>   “这就是一场修行吧，每个人都不知道我们能达到的顶点在哪里”    <br>   <br>   “感觉平时活着就足够筋疲力尽了...自然会去选择逃避，面对‘推免为先书院’的理想也好，回望过去也罢，其实就是逃避现实的方式”    <br>   “你看你这不就明白了吗”        <br></p></blockquote><h4 id="The-Bird’s-Tale"><a href="#The-Bird’s-Tale" class="headerlink" title="The Bird’s Tale"></a>The Bird’s Tale</h4><p>那件事后发了一条朋友圈，只有一张图片，     <br>   《青春猪头》的台词，简介而深刻     <br>   “我又不是为了全人类喜爱而出生的”     <br>   <br>   只是班导在下面发了一条评伦：     <br>   “飞鸟终将越过高山”     <br>   <br>   <br></p><blockquote><p>“我们都一样，漂泊在这片蔚蓝”   <br>  ——Chilichill《飞鸟说》 <br></p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>日常·摩卡·茶话会</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Nichijou</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="/2024/11/24/hello-world/"/>
    <url>/2024/11/24/hello-world/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to <a href="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</a>! This is your very first post. Check <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/">documentation</a> for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html">troubleshooting</a> or you can ask me on <a href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues">GitHub</a>.</p><h2 id="Quick-Start"><a href="#Quick-Start" class="headerlink" title="Quick Start"></a>Quick Start</h2><h3 id="Create-a-new-post"><a href="#Create-a-new-post" class="headerlink" title="Create a new post"></a>Create a new post</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo new <span class="hljs-string">&quot;My New Post&quot;</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/writing.html">Writing</a></p><h3 id="Run-server"><a href="#Run-server" class="headerlink" title="Run server"></a>Run server</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo server<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/server.html">Server</a></p><h3 id="Generate-static-files"><a href="#Generate-static-files" class="headerlink" title="Generate static files"></a>Generate static files</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo generate<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/generating.html">Generating</a></p><h3 id="Deploy-to-remote-sites"><a href="#Deploy-to-remote-sites" class="headerlink" title="Deploy to remote sites"></a>Deploy to remote sites</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo deploy<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/one-command-deployment.html">Deployment</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
